我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来
To the outside world,
我只是个普通的鉴证专员
I'm an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
But secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
但当我女儿从未来时空前来帮忙
But when my daughter came back from the future to help,
她改变了现在
she changed the present.
现在我们的世界比以往更加危险
And now our world is more dangerous than ever.
我是唯一一个来得及拯救世界的人
And I'm the only one fast enough to save it.
我是闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
我相信你也有善良的一面  斯旺
I want to believe that there is good inside of you somewhere, Thawne.
让我来证明吧
Let me prove there is.
那碎片并没有抑制我的超能力
The shards weren't dampening my powers.
而是在移除他们
They were removing them.
我们能做治愈超能力者的解药
We could make a meta-human cure.
厄尔·考克斯  拉尔夫·德比已经改邪归正了
Earl Cox. Ralph Dibny's gone straight.
当你让你新朋友失望的时候
So when you let your new friends down,
给你老朋友打个电话
give your old one a call.
所以你认为这里是蝉的藏身处吗
So he thinks Cicada's hiding out here,
他就躲在这些门后面
just lurking behind those doors.
这是德怀尔房子的内部
It's the inside of Dwyer's house.
你不是结过七次婚吗
Didn't you have, like, seven marriages?
我的确结过七次婚  五位太太  七次婚姻
I did have seven marriages. Five wives, seven marriages.
所以你现在需要告诉我
So I'm gonna need you to tell me right now
你为什么在调查诺拉
why you're investigating Nora.
我的职业就是注意到别人错过的东西
I've made a career out of noticing things that other people miss.
无匹配
你的同伙是谁  诺拉·韦斯特艾伦
Who is your accomplice, Nora West-Allen?
哪里都有个威尔斯
There's always a Wells.
他知道我有同伙了
He knows I'm working with someone.
但他还不知道同伙是谁
But he doesn't know with whom you're working. Not yet.
你怎么知道
How can you be sure?
因为他要是知道
Because if he did,
你爸爸现在马上就到这里来了
your father would be here right now in a flash,
要把他的手穿过我的心脏
threatening to put his hand right through my heart.
艾尔伯德  如果我爸爸发现
Eobard, if my father finds out
你帮我背着他抓蝉
you've been helping me try to catch Cicada behind his back,
他会恨我的
he'll hate me,
而且...
and--
这都可以解决
This can all be fixed.
我可以解决
I can fix this.
怎么解决
How?
一个人... 只有了解另一个人的心思
A man...does not wear another man's face
才能成为那个人
unless he understands his mind.
不仅仅跨越时间
Not just through time
还跨越无穷的地球
but across infinite Earths.
这个歇洛克  他很聪明
This Sherloque, yes, he's brilliant,
但要分散他的注意
but to redirect his gaze,
只需要将他引向他的弱点
one only has to nudge him toward his weakness:
爱
love.
告诉我该怎么做
Tell me what to do.
闪 电 侠
第五季
第十三集
怎么样
Well, what do you think?
挺好看的
Looks great.
我要是把沙发移到靠墙的位置
I mean, I can move the couch against the wall,
会不会好一点
if that'll help.
爱瑞丝  要么放在角落  要么靠墙
Iris, it's just couch in the corner or against the wall
我室内设计的知识就这么多了
is pretty much the extent of my interior design knowledge.
抱歉  亲爱的
I'm sorry, babe.
只是... 只是我
It's--it's just, it's been a week
创办《中城市民》都一个星期了
since I launched the Central City Citizen,
却还很难吸引读者
and I am still struggling to gain readers,
我想我知道为什么了
and I think I just figured out why.
"爱瑞斯·韦斯特艾伦  一位有抱负的网络新闻内行
"Iris West-Allen's first published articles
正式发表的报纸新闻
as an aspiring online news maven
给人的感觉就只有一个
bring one word to mind:
无聊
'boring.'
她的文章平平无奇
Her stories lack the edgy content made popular
而斯宾塞·扬的斯宾谍网这一类网站
by sites such as Spencer Young's
观点鲜明  能够引爆热点
Game-changing Spyn Zone.
总的来说  爱瑞丝·韦斯特艾伦过于保守
In short, Iris West-Allen plays it safe."
爱瑞丝  拜托
Iris, come on.
你不必理会这些
You can't listen to this.
你是个真正的记者
You're a real journalist.
你不必像斯宾塞·扬那样写文章
You don't want to write like Spencer Young.
她根本不屑报道事实
She didn't care about facts.
没错  但至少她写的东西
Yeah, but at least she wrote about things
人们在乎的事
that people cared about,
就像我那时写文章报道迪沃一样
like I did when I was writing about DeVoe.
你想写文章报道蝉
You wanna write about Cicada.
好吧
Fine.
有需要就打给我
Call me if you need me.
-我会在尖端科研实验室  -当然
- I'll be at S.T.A.R. Labs. - Yes, of course.
我有很多东西要查
I've got a lot of digging to do,
而且我有预感从哪开始着手
and I think I have a hunch where to start.
好吧
All right.
你真的觉得这次会成功吗
So you really think this might be it?
西斯科为了证实他的发现
Cisco sent me this sample
给我寄了这个样本
to corroborate his findings,
而且全都证实了
and it all checks out.
我要把最终步骤发给他
I'm sending it back to him for final processing,
但我想我们可能找到了
but I think we may have found a way
抑制超能力者基因组的办法
to suppress the meta genome.
好极了
Great.
这样我们就可以让蝉失去超能力  一劳永逸
Then we can use it to de-power Cicada, stop him for good.
那计划是什么
So what's the plan?
把这个东西灌进麻醉枪里
Put this thing in a tranq gun
像电影《美国狙击手》一样射到他身上吗
and go all "American Sniper" on him?
没那么简单
It's not that simple.
西斯科的突破进展是来自对同卵双胞胎的分析
So Cisco's breakthrough came from analyzing identical twins
而他们被粒子加速器暗物质击中
who were hit by the particle accelerator dark matter,
在这种情况下  一个拥有了超能力
cases where one developed powers
而另一个却没有
and the other didn't.
这两种情况的关键区别在于
The key difference in both cases...
-脑下垂体吗  -没错
- The pituitary gland? - Exactly.
在某些情况下
In some cases,
脑下垂体会新陈代谢出暗物质
the pituitary gland metabolizes dark matter,
从而使超能力得以显现
thus manifesting in meta powers.
所以要把超能力者变成普通人
So to turn a meta-human into a human-human...
就要消除脑下垂体的暗物质
We neutralize the dark matter in the pituitary gland.
但是有一个问题
Except there's one problem.
解药不是立刻见效的
The cure isn't instant.
暗物质已消除
我们必须尽可能让蝉静止不动
We would have to immobilize Cicada for long enough
好让解药起效
for the cure to take effect.
-需要多久  -起码要一分钟吧
- How long will that take? - Best guess, a minute.
要令他静止不动一秒都难如登天了
It's gonna be damn near impossible to hold him still
更别说一分钟了
for one second, much less 60.
但是我们只差一步就成功了
Okay, but we're so close.
肯定还有别的办法
I mean, there's-- there's gotta be something we can do,
即使我们必须打破常规思维
even if we have to think outside the box.
我倒是还有一个办法
I do have one more idea.
范霍恩工业制造了一种和平防暴装置
Van Horn Industries created a peaceful anti-riot device
神经静态场频信号发生器
叫做神经静态场频信号发生器
called a Neuro-Stasis Field Generator.
就是在有限的半径范围内
It's basically a bio-EMP
能使任何生物体无法动弹的生物电磁脉冲
that can immobilize any living organism within a confined radius.
当然  其制造为数不多的装置已经失窃
Of course, the few devices they had built were stolen.
新闻资料
范霍恩工业失窃案
我都不知道从哪里开始找
I wouldn't even know where to begin looking for them.
我知道
I do.
你们能不能不要这么惊讶
Can you at least try not to look so surprised?
如果我们需要这个神经什么的
Look, if we need this, uh, Neo-Matrix whatever it is,
如果这东西失窃了  我知道上哪去找
if it's stolen tech, I think I know where to look.
厄尔·考克斯  拉尔夫说你知道的一些信息
Earl Cox, Ralph says you've got some information
可以帮到我们
that could help us.
结果  你们要找的那个装置
Well, turns out, that device you're looking for
在地下黑市一直有售
has been circulating in the underground black market.
听起来是阿姆内特·布莱克的地盘
Sounds like Amunet Black's territory.
阿姆内特依然下落不明
Eh, Amunet's still MIA.
但信不信由你们  她的前男友接手那个地盘
But believe it or not, her ex-boyfriend is filling the void.
你们有听说过金面人吗
You ever heard of Goldface?
听过  他可是市里
Yeah, he's stolen more weaponized tech
偷取了最多武器装备的罪犯
than any criminal in the city.
中城警局多年来一直在查找他的黑市交易
CCPD's been looking for his black market for years.
对了  他们什么也不会查到的
Oh, aye, and they'll keep on coming up empty.
只要在黑市上付了钱  接着突然间
You pay at the market, and then poof,
你的货第二天就会出现在一个废弃的仓库里
your goods turn up a day later in an abandoned warehouse.
所以当我们拿到想要的东西时
So by the time we get what we want--
金面人早就消失得无影无踪了
Goldface will be long gone.
谢谢你  厄尔
Well, listen, uh, thanks, Earl.
尽量多吃点水果之类的
And, you know, try to eat some fruit or something.
好
Oh, will do.
好了  先生们  后会有期
Right, then, gents. See you around.
但愿吧
Hopefully.
就跟他们说是大拉夫派你们去的
Just tell them Big Raf sent you.
谢谢你的小道消息  厄尔
Thanks for the tip, Earl.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
难道我们就付钱给金面人
We're supposed to pay Goldface
然后让他逃之夭夭吗
and then just let him get away?
别这样  你说我们要跳出圈子思考的
Come on, you said we needed to think outside the box.
这是与魔鬼作交易
This is making a deal with the devil.
不  这是阻止蝉
No, this is stopping Cicada.
我也不喜欢这个计划
Look, I don't like this any more than you do,
但有时候  为达目的可以不择手段
but in some cases, the ends justify the means.
而阻止一个我们根本无法对抗的
And stopping a psychotic meta-killer who we are
超能力疯子杀手  正是这种时候
literally powerless against,  that's one of those cases.
好吧
All right.
我们来这里做什么
What we are doing here?
吉特引进了一种全新的乌龙茶
So Jitters has imported a brand-new oolong tea,
特别稀有  我想尝一尝
and it's super rare and I really want you to try it.
好吧  我现在忙得很
Okay, look, I'm busy right now.
我在调查呢好吗  我没时间搞这些
I'm working, all right? I don't have time for this.
你是在  你在调查什么
Well, what are you-what are you working on?
我在调查一个谜题
Well, I'm working on a mystery,
真是不依不饶  你个小八婆
if you must know, nosy Parker.
什么样的谜题
Well, what kind of mystery?
没准不久后你就会得知
One that maybe I will tell you before too long,
诺拉·韦斯特·艾伦
Nora West-Allen.
很好  那咱们去喝茶吧
Great, so, um, let's grab a tea, then.
行  我就要一杯
All right, we'll have one cup of tea.
外带
To go.
告诉我该怎么做
Tell me what to do.
时间的可塑性非常惊人
It's amazing how malleable the timeline is.
即便是最细小的改变也能引发新的时间线
Even the tiniest refinement can birth a whole new reality,
预 订
上面的一件物品放到了下面
an object above placed below.
一条道路挡住了  引出了全新的另一条
One path blocked leads to a whole new one.
如果你的时机正确
And if your timing is right,
所有一切都会恰到好处
everything falls into place.
不用找零了
Keep the change.
差点以尴尬的方式死了
That would have been an embarrassing way to go.
真是的  死于脱因咖啡
My gosh. Death by decaf.
被馥芮白咖啡打倒
Flattened by flat white.
这个女人很特殊
This woman is special.
帮他赢取她的爱
Help him win her love,
他的注意力就会从你移到她身上
and his attention moves from you right onto her.
-瑞内·艾德勒  -艾德勒小姐  歇洛克·福尔摩斯
- Renée Adler. - Ah, Miss Adler. Sherloque Wells.
要不我请你吃司康饼还是什么来报答你
Can I buy you a scone or something to repay you for saving my life?
司康  好  吃一晚上  我是说好
Scone? Yes, all night. I mean yes.
-太好了  -谢谢你
- Great. - Thank you very much.
咱们吃司康饼的时候要谈论些什么呢
What we shall talk about while we eat our scones, I wonder?
或许是  看你的形体和姿态
Maybe about, given your grace and your posture,
谈你的芭蕾舞训练
your years of ballet training?
四岁就开始了
Since I was four.
你的感觉真敏锐
Wow, you're really perceptive.
是种很谦卑的天赋
Well, it's a modest talent, I suppose.
你还注意到我什么了
Notice anything else about me?
挑战接受
Challenge accepted.
东海岸女孩
Um, well, East Coast girl?
没错
Yes.
是小镇里出来的  或许是港口小镇
From a small village, maybe, um, by a bay?
工作和书有关  图书管理员
Work with books? A librarian?
在大学工作
At a university?
住在地铁周边  小复式公寓
Live by a train station, small split-level pad?
你有只狗  老狗
You, um, have a dog. Older dog.
柯基犬  不过  关于那司康饼
Corgi. Anyway, about that scone--
-好吧  离我远点  -什么
- Okay, stay away from me. - What?
我不知道你监视我多久了  但是到此为止
I don't know how long you've been watching me, but it ends now.
不是  不是
No, no, no.
不然我就报警  跟踪狂
Or I'm calling CCPD, stalker.
艾德勒小姐  我没...
No, uh, Miss Adler. I...
-夏洛克  -歇洛克
- Sherlock! - Sherloque.
你对她说那些干什么
Why did you say all that stuff to her?
就是跳过寒暄  不行吗
You know, skip the small talk, no?
-不行  -我还有调查要做呢
- No. - I have work to do.
别别  虽然我不是恋爱专家
No, no, no, um, I just--I'm not really a romance expert,
但我看到出你很喜欢她
but I just feel like you were really into her.
是  也许有点喜欢她
Well, yes, maybe a little into her.
好  那就别那么快放弃啊
Okay, so don't give up so fast, you know?
也许你可以  找个办法去道歉
Maybe you could, um, try to find a way to say I'm sorry
或许我还能帮你一下
and I could help you with that.
谁能拒绝这种提议呢
How could one say no to that?
好了  我们快到位了
All right, we're approaching the position.
收到
Copy.
这些是黑市的坐标
These are the coordinates of the black market.
斯诺和冰霜小队待命做后援
Team Snow and Frost are standing by for backup.
好了  我们现在做什么
Okay. What do we do now?
我想是念魔咒的时候了
I guess we say the magic words.
街上铺满了黄金
The streets are paved with gold.
可能你说的声音不够大
Maybe you didn't say it loud enou--
目标丢失
巴里  拉尔夫
Barry? Ralph?
超能力手铐
Meta cuffs?
没错  带有炸药的
That's right, power-dampening cuffs
超能力抑制手铐
fitted with an explosive charge
以防你们都是超能力者
in case you're both metas.
告诉我  是谁派你们来的
So tell me, who sent you?
太棒了  看看他们变得多有威胁性
That's really sweet. Look how threatening they're trying to be.
各位
Boys, uh...
我们很感激这一切  但是你们可以放松点
We really appreciate all this, but you can relax.
大拉夫派我们过来的
Big Raf sent us.
大拉夫
Big Raf, huh?
好吧
All right, then.
先生们  欢迎来到市场
Gentlemen, welcome to the market.
所以没有人知道我们在哪里  包括我们自己
So nobody, including us, knows where we are right now.
而且我们完全没有超能力
And we are totally powerless.
老兄  如果我们在这里走错了一步
Dude, if we make the wrong move in here,
手铐就会是最不需要担心的东西
these cuffs are gonna be the least of our worries.
新计划
New game plan.
我们活力二人组的对手会找到场频信号发生器
The antihero of our dynamic duo will find the Field Generator.
你呆在这里  尽量别表现得像是警察
And you're just gonna stay here and try not to look like a cop.
-或者是超级英雄  -好
- Or a superhero. - Okay.
或者你的任何真实身份
Or really anything you actually are.
快去吧  我没事
Just go. I'm fine.
你看起来像是个有品位的买家
You look like a discerning consumer.
我给你介绍一下这件武器好吗
Might I interest you in a little firepower?
不用了
No, I'm good.
你来武器市场却不买武器吗
Come to a weapons market and you don't want any weapons?
我说过不用了  我是来找一些特别的东西
I said I'm good. I'm here for something special.
有什么会比中城警局杀手更特别呢
What's more special than a CCPD killer?
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
这就是这些宝贝的出众之处
That's what's great about these babies.
能烧穿警用防弹衣
Burn through police-issued body armor.
我叫它宴会主持人  你自己试一试
I call them toastmasters. Try it for yourself.
我等不及想看警察看到这武器时脸上的表情了
Can't wait to see cops' faces when these hit the streets.
或者他们脸上还能剩下什么
Or what's left of their faces.
-把这些全买下要多少钱  -全部吗
- How much for all of them? - Uh, all of them?
每个买家有购买上限
There's a limit per customer.
你可以去请求金面人批准
I guess I could ask Goldface for approval.
不如我们两个人来解决这个问题
No, why don't we just work this out between us?
把你手里的武器都买下要多少钱
How much will it cost to take all these off your hands?
谢谢你来见我  奥斯麦克先生
Thank you for meeting with me, Mr. Osmack.
叫我布兰特  别客气
Oh, call me Brent. And it's no problem.
任何关于工会改革的采访都是有意义的
Any interview about union reform is time well spent.
工人们有什么意见吗
What about workers' opinions?
我想作为经理  你一定总能收到他们的意见
I imagine, as a manager, you must get them all the time.
我比大部分员工的妻子都更了解他们
Yeah, I know most of my guys better than their wives.
我猜有人令你出乎意料时一定很难接受
So I guess it must be difficult when one of them surprises you.
比如大家都在谈论的
Like that, um--that killer that
那个杀手  奥林·德怀尔
everyone's talking about, Orlin Dwyer.
他说过什么表达自己感受的话
Did he ever say anything that indicated how he was feeling
或者他想要做什么吗
or what he was up to?
无可奉告
No comment.
他有没有给你留下任何关于
Okay, well, did he give you any kind of clue about
他可能在哪里的线索
where he might be now?
我说了无可奉告
I said no comment.
他威胁你了吗
Did he threaten you?
我知道你很害怕
Look, I know you're scared.
去年迪沃袭击的时候很多人也很害怕
A lot of people were scared when DeVoe attacked last year.
但是闪电侠打败了他
But the Flash defeated him,
有一部分原因是我写的文章
partially because I wrote these articles
鼓励人们提供信息
that encouraged people to come forward with information.
我们可以阻止德怀尔
We can stop Dwyer.
好吧  他的工资会寄到一个邮政信箱
Okay, his paychecks went to a P.O. Box.
但是有一次出了问题
But there was a problem once,
我只能转寄到他的表哥家
and I had to forward to his cousin's house.
他的名字是罗比
Uh, his name was, uh, Robbie something.
罗比  罗比·伯恩
Robbie-- Robbie Byrne.
太好了
That's great.
我告诉你  兄弟  我没有权利
I'm telling you, man, I don't have the authority
-批准这样大规模的购买  -听着
- to okay a purchase that large. - Uh, listen--
打扰一下  巴塞洛缪  可以说句话吗
Excuse me, um, Bartholomew, a word?
就说一句话
Just a word, yeah.
你到底在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
这个人有大量杀害警察的枪
Okay, this guy has got crates of cop-killing guns.
你更希望他卖给犯罪们吗
Would you prefer he sells them to criminals?
我希望你不要暴露我们的身份
I would prefer that you not blow our cover,
而你即将暴露
and you're going to blow our cover.
拜托了  兄弟  就十分钟
Come on, man, I asked you to turn off
不要扮演超级英雄
hero mode for, like, ten minutes.
好吧  随便你
Okay, all right, whatever.
我们别在这吵  好吗
Let's not argue about this here, all right?
你找到场频信号发生器了吗
Did you find the Field Generator?
我当然找到了
Of course I did.
不过如果你知道在谁手里肯定不高兴
But you're not gonna like who has it.
你们好吗  欢迎
What up? What up? And welcome.
我听说我这有样东西你们很感兴趣
I hear something special in my collection's caught your attention.
没错  神经静态
You heard right. The Neuro-Stasis--
神经静态场频信号发生器吗
Neuro-Stasis Field Generator?
如果使用得当  这东西威力无穷
It's a nasty bit of business, if used properly.
我们不打算拿它做什么善事
There's nothing proper about the way we're gonna use it.
同类人
My kind of people.
好  我们来聊聊
Okay. Let's chop it up.
谈谈这笔交易
Let's make a deal.
我们到底还谈不谈了
Look, we gonna do a deal or what?
闭嘴
Shut your mouth.
除非你想失去一只手
Unless you wanna be one-handed.
我想你也不愿意
Thought not.
是这样
See, here's the thing.
人渣能识别人渣
Scum recognizes scum.
我就是个人渣
I'm scum.
我能活这么久全靠慧眼识人
And I've survived this long by recognizing the same.
好比你  就是个渣子
Like you. You're scum.
我一眼就能看出来
I sniffed you coming a mile away.
我该谢谢你吗
Thanks?
但是你的同伴  我看不清楚
But your partner, I don't sniff nothing on him.
这我很担心
And that worries me.
问题来了
So the question is...
你是谁
Who are you?
我能为他担保  他只是
Well, I can vouch for him. He's just--
我让你闭嘴
I said shut your mouth!
我要听他自己说
I wanna hear it from him.
我再最后问一次
I'm only gonna ask once moe.
你到底是谁
Who are you?
我是不存在的
I'm nobody.
没被逮捕
No arrests.
不曾被定罪
No convictions.
即便在星城博物馆用原子化安定剂
Not for the Star City Museum heist
迷晕了保安进行抢劫
where atomized Lorazepam knocked the guards out
还有上月在联邦储备银行用酸弹
or the acid bomb that blew open
炸开了保险库之后
the Federal Reserve vault last month.
是你干的吗
That was you?
警方不这么认为
Not according to police reports.
我留下的唯一证据就是红鲱鱼
Because the only evidence I leave behind are red herrings
让那些傻逼警察去查
for idiot cops to chase down.
你想知道我是谁吗
You wanna know who I am?
你可以叫我化学家
You can call me the Chemist.
不过我还真不在乎你怎么称呼我
But I really don't care what you call me.
别再浪费我的时间了
Just stop wasting my time.
他可比你牛逼多了
You should let him do the talking.
是啊  大伙都这么说  交易继续吗
Yeah, I get that a lot. Uh, so we back in business?
剧情反转
With a twist.
今晚有笔大买卖
Got a big job tonight.
我们需要化学家这样的人
Could use a guy like the Chemist
帮助我们掩饰行踪
to cover our tracks.
你帮我弄到我需要的
You help me get what I want,
我就给你你想要的
I'll give you what you want.
你到底要什么
And what exactly do you want?
伊沃实验室有一台尖端的3D打印机
Ivo Labs has this cutting-edge 3-D printer.
卖给了一家医院
Sold it to some hospital.
这台3D打印机有什么特别
What's so special about a 3-D printer?
它能够打印人造器官
This one prints artificial organs.
如果我搞到它  最高竞价者
If I've got it, I can sell life
就能从我这里买一条命
to the highest bidder.
你想让我们去抢一家医院
You want us to rob a hospital?
当然不是  我又不是魔鬼
Of course not. I'm not a monster.
我要你们在它还没送到医院之前
I want you to rob the lab before it ever gets
去抢实验室
to the hospital.
小伙子们  笑一个
Smile, boys.
今晚你们为金面人卖命
Tonight you're working for Goldface.
有史以来最好的生日礼物  拉尔夫
Best birthday present ever, Ralph.
连 接
- [法语]嗨 -你来了  太好了
- Allô! - Oh, good, you're here.
因为你要求我帮助你的爱情生活
So since you let me agree to help you with your love life...
-没错  -我有一个大胆的想法
- Right. - I came up with an unusual idea.
-棒极了  -是的
- Spectacular. - Mm-hmm.
我向你的前妻们求助了
I have asked your ex-wives for help.
很棒  什么
Great. What?
五个女人都嫁给你是有原因的
Five women married you for a reason.
还有谁比她们更合适去问
So who better to ask
为什么她们会爱上你呢
why they fell in love with you than them?
好的  除了
Okay, except--
我一开始不认为她们有谁会同意
I didn't think any of them would agree,
但是实际上她们四位都欣然接受了
but four of them actually jumped at the chance.
-她们当然会  -为什么
- Of course they did. - Mm-hmm.
因为我欠她们钱
Because I owe them money.
我拖欠了她们全部的赡养费
I'm behind on all the alimony payments,
她们不知道我在哪个地球  直至现在
and they don't know what Earth I'm on, until now.
-什么  -没错
- What? - That's right.
你好  侦探
Hello, Detective.
你好  切丽
Hello, chérie.
你七次娶的都是同一个女人
You married the same woman seven times?
她是我的真命天女
Well, she's the one for me.
亲爱的  你不可能一辈子都躲着我们
Darling, you can't run forever.
我们总能找到你
We'll always find you.
你违反了赡养费法第1152条
You're in violation of alimony order 1152.
该付钱了
Time to pay up!
女士们
Ladies.
我们知道你让超人
We know you had Superman
帮你把赡养费送到地球三十八的前妻
deliver your alimony to your ex on Earth-38.
-什么  -你以为我们都不交谈的吗
- What? - You think we don't all talk?
我希望她们都不要交谈
I was hoping they don't all talk.
-不  我们交谈  -我们得谈谈
- Oh, no, we talk. - We have to talk.
-我们常常在一起  -是的
- We get together all the time. - Oh, we do.
除了我一直都打不通你电话
Except I can never get you on the phone.
我发信息
I text.
我懂  你想要你的钱  对吗
Look, I understand. You want your money, right?
所以也许我们可以  可以达成一致
So maybe we can--maybe we can come to an agreement, hmm?
我们有过协议  就是你目前违反的那个
We had an agreement, one that you're currently in breach of.
女士们
Uh, ladies.
女士们  这只是一个很大的误解
Ladies, just a big misunderstanding here.
很大的误解
Big misunderstanding.
我想你们都来这里是
I thought you were all coming here
为了帮助歇洛克
to help Sherloque.
歇洛克
Sherloque.
帮助他
Help him?
你帮不了一个觉得自己什么都懂的人
You can't help a man who thinks he knows everything.
就像当年一连串线索让他认为
Yeah, like the time clues led him to believe it'd be romantic
在我们婚礼上放果蝠很浪漫一样
to release fruit bats at our wedding.
那是因为她当时在保护濒危物种
It's because she support the endangered species,
所以我就说释放果蝠
so I say fruit bat.
我真的  我是想表达关切
I do. I was being thoughtful.
在结婚纪念日上  他给我买了一只小狗
Oh, for our anniversary, he bought me a puppy dog.
这  这真的不  这还蛮好的
That's--that's not really-- That's kind of nice.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我对于小狗十分过敏
I am deathly allergic to puppy dogs.
那些皮屑让我的喉咙...
The dander makes my throat just...
这是真的  但研究表明更多地接触过敏原
It's true, but studies show that more exposure to the allergens,
能建立你的免疫系统
it builds up your immune system,
所以我是在给你一个健康的生活
so I'm trying to give you a healthy life.
再一次  我真的很体贴
Again, thoughtful on my part.
至少他没有推论出
Well, at least he didn't deduce that
最好的分手方式是伪造自己死亡
the nicest way to break up with you was to fake his own death.
这就不那么关切了
Not so thoughtful.
两次
Twice!
第二次就是你的错了  亲爱的
Oh, that last one really was on you, dear.
是的  认真的
Yeah, seriously.
如果你下个月再不付钱的话
Look, there's gonna be a real death here
就可能会引发真正的死亡
if you don't pay us our money back next month
包含利息
with interest.
我们现在知道你在哪里
We know where you are now.
加上  我们有很棒的赡养费追偿代理
Plus, we got a great alimony recovery agent
名字叫做穿越者
by the name of Breacher.
穿越者
Breacher?
抓紧时间  夏洛克
Ticktock, Sherlock.
歇洛克  你要去哪里
Sherloque. Where you're going?
-歇洛克  -我喜欢你的发音
- Sherloque. - Oh, I like how you say it.
我不是故意说得那么无情
I don't mean to sound heartless,
但是  亲爱的
but, darling,
不是每个人都注定有一段感情
not everyone is meant for a relationship.
有些人就是注定孤独一生
Some people are just destined to be alone.
歇洛克  我
Sherloque, I...
我们五分钟后出发
We roll out in five.
听着  我不用问你
Look, uh, I don't have to ask you
都知道你对此有什么感觉
how you feel about this.
从医院里偷窃  这真的
Stealing from a hospital, that's...
这真的远远超出我们的预期
That's way more than we bargained for.
如果你不想干这事  我...
So if you don't want to do this, I'm--
我会做的
I'll do it.
你真的会
You will?
是啊  我有选择余地吗
Yeah, what choice do I have?
接这份工作时  你警告过我头脑要清醒
You warned me to get my head on straight for this job,
但我没有
and I didn't.
本来金面人准备好给我们所需要的东西
You had Goldface ready to give us what we needed,
但我为了不让枪支出现在大街上而搞砸了
and I blew it trying to get those guns off the street,
最终到了这地步
and here we are.
巴里  这不是你的错
Barry, this is not your fault.
是的  就是
Yeah, it is.
你说的没错
And you were right.
假如我要阻止蝉  我不能吝惜
If I wanna stop Cicada, I can't be so precious
弄脏闪电侠的手
about getting the Flash's hands dirty.
有时为达到目的  可以不择手段
Sometimes the ends justify the means.
我现在明白了
I get that now.
我们赶紧了断此事吧
Let's just get this over with.
你又是谁
Who the hell are you?
对不起  门没有上锁
Sorry, um, the door was unlocked.
我是一名记者  我...
I'm a reporter. I'm--
我想找这里的房东  罗比·伯恩
Uh, I'm looking for the owner, Robbie Byrne.
我就是罗比
I'm Robbie.
所以
So...
你要写什么类型的故事
what kind of story you writing?
是一份调查报告
It's an investigative report about
关于在这附近出现
lead leaking into the water pipes
铅泄漏到水管的问题
in this neighborhood.
是这样吗
Is that so?
是  是的
Yeah. Um, yeah.
如果可以的话  你回答几个问题
And it would be, um, very helpful if you could answer
将会很有帮助
a few questions for me.
好吧
All right.
但我并没有发现水有什么问题
But I haven't noticed anything strange in the water.
这就是铅的可怕之处
That's the scary thing about lead.
若出现首发症状  可能就要
I mean, the first sign would probably be a trip
被送到医院了
to the hospital.
婴幼儿尤其易受感染
Young children are especially susceptible.
你有一个女儿吗
Do you have a daughter?
我过去有
I used to.
听到这件事我很抱歉
I'm sorry to hear that.
那你怎么样
And what about you?
我
Me?
我从来都没感觉这么好过
I'm feeling better than ever.
铅中毒会以各种方式
Well, lead poisoning can present itself
呈现出来
in a variety of ways.
听着  现在很晚了
Look, it's late.
我也准备去睡觉了  所以
And I've got to get to bed soon, so...
当然  伯恩先生  我明白
Of course, Mr. Byrne. I understand.
我还有一些问题
Um, I still have a few more questions.
我明天可以随时去办公室找你
I mean, I could always come to your office tomorrow,
如果你愿意的话
if you like.
你愿意我明天见你吗
Would you prefer I see you tomorrow, then?
不
No.
我们现在就了结这事吧
Let's finish this now.
在泡茶吗
Making tea?
不   在煮浓缩咖啡
No, making an espresso
因为我的头脑需要更多的咖啡因
because the mind needs more caffeine.
那只是热水
Um, that's just hot water.
不  不  这
No, no, it--
该死的
Nom de Dieu.
歇洛克  你知道你前妻说的话
Sherloque, you know that stuff your ex-wife said
不是真的  对吗
isn't true, right?
不  我注定孤独一生
No, I'm destined to be alone.
-不  你不是  -我是的
- No, you're not. - Yes, I am.
听着
Listen.
你把爱情看成是可以解开的谜团
You treat love like it's a mystery that can be solved.
但是你不能推断出自己的结局是否幸福
But you can't deduce your way to a happy ending.
你只需要让它一步一步来
You just have to let it come one step at a time
享受你所处的每一阶段
and enjoy whatever step you're in.
好的  听好了
Okay, listen up.
进去  出来
Get in, get out.
我们的人说里面空无一人
Our guy on the inside said the place is empty,
你们都会有密码和通行证
and you all have the code and the pass cards.
将你们的武器从击晕
Switch your weapons from stun
转换到去见上帝
to meet your maker.
我们出发
Let's go.
走
Go.
巴里  让我检查一下你的步枪
Barry, let me check your rifle.
我觉得它需要一个新的弹夹
I think it needs a new clip.
什么
What?
我好像把手机落在里面了
Left my phone in there.
可以帮我看一下吗
Can you check for me?
我们要...
We gotta--
-安全  -上上上
- Clear. - Move, move, move.
拉尔夫  手机不在这里  这有...
Ralph, there's no phone, man. There's--
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你在干什  拉尔夫
What are you--Ralph!
你是对的  巴里
You're right, Barry.
-闪电侠不必如此  -什么
- Flash doesn't have to do this. - What?
但我能
But I can.
拉尔夫
Ralph.
拉尔夫  让我出去
Ralph, let me out!
我可以支援你
I can back you up, man!
别自己去
Don't go alone!
保持干净
装货区
拉尔夫
Ralph!
Ralph.
我能帮你  别一个人去
I can have your back, man! Don't go alone!
化学家在哪里
Where's the Chemist?
他说什么我们在卡车里留下了
He said something about us leaving an orgy of evidence
一大票证据  他正在处理呢
in the truck. He's handling it.
好了  分散开始搜索
All right, fan out and search.
找到后发信号
Signal back when you find it.
匿名的罪犯同伙
Hey, anonymous criminal colleague,
这就是了
this is it.
器官接受者信息
这包装有点过分了
Kind of overkill with the packaging.
器官接受者信息
这里不是图书馆  老兄
Yo, this ain't a library, man.
帮我搭把手啊
You wanna give me a hand?
好  给你两手怎么样
Yeah, how about two?
对不起  也没对不起  老兄
Sorry, not sorry, pal.
这个宝宝得进医院
This baby's going to a hospital.
说实话  我从没喜欢过你
Honestly, I never liked you.
把这个垃圾带到卡车上处理掉
Take this trash out to the truck for disposal.
还有他的朋友
And his friend too.
走吧  走吧
Come on, come on.
好了  打包下
All right, let's pack it up.
动作快
Chop-chop.
砖头
Brick!
拉尔夫
Ralph!
谢谢  但声明一下
Well, thank you, but for the record,
我的意思是把砖头扔给我
I meant throw the brick to me.
我是要扔给你啊
I was trying to throw it to you.
我看你也不能忍了
I see you couldn't go through with it either.
在我看到那些小孩子之后
Not after I saw those little kids.
卡夫和打印机在里面呢
Carver's in there with the printer.
他们有好多枪  我们没有任何超能力
There's a lot of guns. We don't have any powers.
但这东西有击晕选项
But these do have a stun setting.
走吧
Come on.
简直是家常便饭  各位
All in a day's work, people.
-掩护我  -散开  散开
- Cover me! - Break, break, break!
-走  小心  -走  走  走
- Go! Watch it! - Go, go, go, go!
-那是怎么回事  -我绊倒了
- Where'd that come from? - I tripped.
咱们去拿打印机
Let's get that printer.
巴里
Barry!
别动
Don't move!
我就知道天天玩《荒野大镖客》会有帮助
I knew all that "Red Dead" would pay off.
好帮手可真难找
Good help's so hard to find.
你俩  去码头  马上
Both of you, loading dock. Now.
走
Go.
实验室 员工通道
好孩子
Good boys.
我还期望你们不需要让爸爸用到腰带呢
I was hoping you wouldn't make Daddy use his belt.
既然你们听从了命令
Since you obeyed me,
我就不炸掉你们的胳臂了
I'm not gonna blow your arms off.
我要用更传统的方式
I'm gonna kill you
杀了你们
in a more traditional way.
我发誓...
And I prom--
他真的应该先搜我们的身
He really should have frisked us first.
你也看到了  我的金子
See, that's the thing-- my gold...
不仅仅是装饰
It don't just make me look pretty.
好吧  戈尔迪·霍恩  来开始吧
All right, Goldie Hawn. Let's do this.
既然我要做器官捐献生意
Since I'm going into the organ donor business,
你应该庆幸自己的尸体将拿来做善业
you'll be happy to know that your corpse is going to good cost
让我发财
making me rich.
你为什么对他发火
Hey! Why you so mad at him?
又不是他用假背景故事骗了你
He's not the one that made you fall for a fake backstory.
金面人  更像是愚人金
Goldface, huh? More like Fool's Gold.
好在他不知道这枪没有子弹
Good thing he didn't know this wasn't loaded.
他还活着
He's alive.
没错  我们也是
Yeah, and so are we.
谢谢你
Thanks to you.
化学家
The Chemist?
我  我该走了
Well, I, um-- I should get going.
谢谢你  感激不尽
Thank you so much. I really appreciate it.
你来这的时候可没有拿那个包
You didn't have that bag when you came in here.
我们会赢的
We're gonna beat you.
你伤得很重
Well, you got pretty banged up,
但你的超能力已经发挥作用了
but your powers are already working their magic.
没用永久损伤的迹象
No signs of permanent damage.
貌似今晚唯一损失就是我们的任务
Guess the only real loss today was our mission.
也对
Yeah.
不  我们会找到其他办法找到场频信号发生器
No, we'll find another way to get the Field Generator.
再说了  我们今天是赢了一场
And besides, we did have another win today.
我们没用超能力就打败了一个强大的超能力者
We took down a powerful meta-human without our powers.
这告诉我们  即便蝉会抑制超能力
That's a good reminder that even when Cicada dampens us,
我们还是有办法战斗
we have other ways to fight.
未知来电
你好
Hello?
爱瑞丝
Iris?
德怀尔不见了
Dwyer's gone.
我去接爱瑞丝
I'll get Iris.
-我这边什么都没有  -楼上也是
- I got nothing in here. - Ditto upstairs.
没有任何证据
Yeah, there's no evidence here
表明他去了哪里
that points to where he went.
找到你需要的装置了吗
Did you find that device you needed?
或许我们不需要那个
Maybe we don't need it.
我知道怎么给蝉注射解药了
I know how to give the cure to Cicada.
我知道他的弱点
I know his weakness.
打扰一下
Uh, pardon.
-我可以为您续杯吗  -我的天
- May I offer you a refill? - Oh, God.
不不不  等等等
No, no, no. Wait, wait, wait.
我有事要告诉你  别紧张
I need to tell you something. Don't be alarmed.
我不是个跟踪狂  我是个警探
I am not a stalker. I'm a detective.
所以我知道你的情况
This is how I knew all these facts about you.
我推断出的
I deduced them.
这么说有点傲慢  但是我很擅长那个
It's immodest to say, but I happen to be quite good at it.
-证明一下  -什么
- Prove it. - Pardon?
证明给我看
Show me. Do, um...
推断那个男人
Do that guy.
-接受挑战  -好极了
- Challenge accepted. - Great.
如果你看他饮料的大小
So if you look at the size of his drink,
相对于他的大块头太小了
small relative to his body mass.
又有犹豫又有喝饮料的
And the hesitation but also the enjoyment with which
享受  这是基本的
he consumes his beverage, it's elementary.
这是一个对乳制品过敏的人
This is a man who has a dairy allergy
却又喜欢牛奶拿铁
but still prefers to drink milk lattes,
但是不出意外
but not without consequence.
等等看
Oh, wait for it. And...
-噢  -你瞧
- Oh. - Et voilà.
我的天
Oh, my gosh.
-你很厉害啊  -我能说什么
- You are really good at this. - What can I say?
是个谦卑的天赋  但是我得道歉
It is a modest talent. But I must apologize for--
怎么说的来着  把你吓到了
how do they say-- creeping you out.
但如果你能原谅我
But if perhaps you would allow yourself to forgive me,
我能请你喝杯茶来补偿你
then I could buy you a tea to make it up to you.
我要去上班了
Well, I have to go to work now.
-好的  -但  但是我
- Ah, all right, no. - But--but I--
-是的  -改天你可以给我打电话
- Yes, of course. - You can call me sometime.
真的
Really?
谢谢
Ah, merci.
我期待着  改天
I look forward to, um, sometime.
-我也是  -那
- Me too. - Mm. So...
谢谢
Thanks.
-你没事吧  -老天
- Oh, you all right? - Oh, gosh.
我应该在三岁时
I guess I should have started ballet
就练芭蕾的  对吧
when I was three, right?
当然
Of course, yes.
-再见  -再会  艾德勒小姐
- Okay, bye. - Au revoir, Miss Adler.
你太棒了
Ah, you're amazing.
你是个超能力者
You're a meta.
闪 电 侠
尖端科研实验室
电脑  开
Computer on.
无匹配
关掉诺拉·韦斯特·艾伦文件
Close Nora West-Allen file.
打开蝉案例
Open Cicada casework.
好了
All right.
他不会伤害你
He will not harm you.
如果你的任务成功
If your mission is successful,
你的秘密就是安全的
your secret is safe.
你和我可以继续我们的计划了
And you and I are free to continue what we started.